

# **ANDREW STEELE**

FRONT END DEVELOPER | ANDREWTHECREATOR.COM 710 OLD DALLAS RD, CHATTANOOGA, TN 37405

# **OBJECTIVE**

I am a skilled and passionate front end developer with over 10 years of professional experience. I love coding in the front end, where I can work to realize the vision of designers, provide the interface for the backend developers, and guide the end user through a frictionless and enjoyable experience.

## **SKILLS**

- > JavaScript
- React
- > Ember
- > CSS/SASS
- > HTML
- Node.JS
- Ruby on Rails
- ▶ PHP
- ➢ Git

# **EDUCATION**

## **B.S. IN BROADCASTING**

Toccoa Falls College, 2003

## **EXPERIENCE**

### FRONT END ARCHITECT • INFOARMOR • 2017 - 2018

- Lead a team of five in a complete remake of InfoArmor's Identity Theft Prevention client portal (PHP Smarty Templates into React)
- Created a new login and authentication system
- Used React, MobX, JavaScript, CSS/SASS, and HTML/JSX

## FRONT END DEVELOPER • FREELANCE/CONTRACTOR • 2015 - 2017

- ADP Sr. React Consultant. Architected a drag-and-drop, WYSIWYG desktop application for creating page layouts which compiled into a JSON specification. Used React, JavaScript, Node. JS, and Electron.
- Remine UI/UX Developer. Completed version 1.0 of their big-data real estate analytics app; also re-did their website. *Used JavaScript, CSS/SASS, Bootstrap.*
- **Rezli** Front End Developer. Responsible for the front end redesign and implementation of their social network for video gamers. *Used React, JavaScript, CSS/SASS, Ruby on Rails, Slim Templates, HTML.*
- CodeScience UI Engineer. Developed single-page applications
  (SPAs) both on and off the Salesforce platform, including an Excel-like
  spreadsheet app and updates to Salesforce's blog platform. Used
  JavaScript, Ember, Apex, Salesforce, CSS/SASS.

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER • ORTHOBANC • 2015

- Created a database administration GUI for internal use
- Provided backend API creation support
- Used Ember, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS/SASS, Node.JS, Sails.JS

### SR. TECHNICAL CONSULTANT • FIRMA8 • 2009 - 2015

- Created an e-learning system, a live-streaming video platform, a translation plugin for Adobe InDesign, website and document translator, a translating chat system for call centers, and an online video/audio player built with HTML and JS (no backend)
- Produced product demo videos, screencasts, and manuals
- Used JavaScript, CSS/SASS, Ruby on Rails, PHP.







